So for the past year and a half,
إذن في السنة والنصف الماضية،
my team at Push Pop Press
فريقي في Push Pop Press
and Charlie Melcher and Melcher Media
وتشارلي ميلتشر وإعلام ميلتشر
have been working on creating
كانوا يعملون على إنشاء
the first feature-length interactive book.
أول كتاب تفاعلي طويل.
It's called "Our Choice"
أطلق عليه "خيارنا"
and the author is Al Gore.
والكاتب هو آل غور.
It's the sequel to "An Inconvenient Truth,"
وهو تكملة لـفيلم "حقيقة غير مريحة"
and it explores all the solutions
ويستعرض كافة الحلول
that will solve the climate crisis.
التي ستحل المشكلة المناخية.
The book starts like this. This is the cover.
الكتاب يبدأ هكذا. هذا هو الغلاف.
As the globe spins,
وبدوران الكرة الأرضية،
we can see our location,
يمكن أن نرى مكاننا.
and we can open the book
ثم يمكن أن نفتح الكتاب
and swipe through the chapters
ونتحرك خلال الفصول
to browse the book.
لتصفح الكتاب.
Or, we can scroll through the pages at the bottom.
أو، يمكن الإنتقال نزولا خلال الصفحات في الأسفل.
And if we wanted to zoom into a page,
وإن أردتم تكبير صفحة،
we can just open it up.
يمكننا أن نفتحها فقط.
And anything you see in the book,
وأي شيء ترونه في الكتاب،
you can pick up with two fingers
يمكن أن يلتقط بواسطة أصبعين
and lift off the page
ويرفع خارج الصفحة
and open up.
ويفتح.
And if you want to go back
وإن أردت العودة
and read the book again,
وقراءة الكتاب مجددا،
you just fold it back up and put it back on the page.
تقوم فقط بطيها وإعادتها إلى الصفحة.
And so this works the same way; you pick it up and pop it open.
وبالتالي هذا يشتغل بنفس الطريقة؛ تلتقطه وتفتحه بسرعة.
(Audio) Al Gore: I consider myself
(صوت) آل غور: أعتبر نفسي
among the majority
واحد من أغلبية
who look at windmills and feel
تنظر إلى طواحين الهواء وتحس
they're a beautiful addition to the landscape.
أنها إضافة جميلة إلى المنظر الطبيعي.
Mike Matas: And so throughout the whole book,
مايك ماتاس: وهكذا خلال الكتاب كله،
Al Gore will walk you through and explain the photos.
آل غور سيرشدكم ويوضح الصور.
This photo, you can you can even see on an interactive map.
هذه الصورة، يمكنكم حتى أن تروا خريطة تفاعلية.
Zoom into it and see where it was taken.
نقوم بالتكبير ونرى أين تم أخذها.
And throughout the book,
وعلى طول الكتاب،
there's over an hour of documentary footage
هناك ما يزيد عن ساعة من اللقطات الوثائقية
and interactive animations.
والرسوم المتحركة التفاعلية.
So you can open this one.
وهكذا يمكن أن تفتحوا هذه.
(Audio) AG: Most modern wind turbines consist of a large ...
(صوت) آل غور: معظم برامج الريح المعاصرة تتشكل من ..
MM: It starts playing immediately.
مايك ماتاس: تبدأ في الإشتغال مباشرة.
And while it's playing, we can pinch and peak back at the page,
وفيما هي تشتغل، يمكن أن قرص وتقليص للعودة إلى الصفحة،
and the movie keeps playing.
والفيلم مستمر في الإشتغال.
Or we can zoom out to the table of contents,
أو يمكن أن نصغر إلى جدول المحتويات،
and the video keeps playing.
والفيديو لا يزال مشتغلا.
But one of the coolest things in this book
لكن أحد أهم الأمور المميزة في هذا الكتاب
are the interactive infographics.
هي الرسوم المعلوماتية التفاعلية.
This one shows the wind potential
هذه تعرض قدرة الرياح
all around the United States.
في أرجاء الولايات المتحدة.
But instead of just showing us the information,
لكن بدل عرض المعلومات فقط،
we can take our finger and explore,
يمكن أن نحرك اصبعنا ونتصفح،
and see, state by state,
ونرى، ولاية بولاية،
exactly how much wind potential there is.
بالضبط ما قدرة الرياح الموجودة.
We can do the same for geothermal energy
يمكن ان نقوم بنفس الشيء بالنسبة للطاقة الحرارية الأرضية
and solar power.
والطاقة الشمسية.
This is one of my favorites.
هذه إحدى مفضلاتي.
So this shows ...
إذن هذه تعرض..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
When the wind is blowing,
حين تهب الرياح،
any excess energy coming from the windmill
أي فائض طاقة قادم من المطحنة الهوائية
is diverted into the battery.
يحول إلى البطارية.
And as the wind starts dying down,
وبتراجع قوة الرياح،
any excess energy will be diverted back into the house --
كل فائض طاقة يحول إلى المنزل --
the lights never go out.
الأضواء لا تنطفئ أبدا.
And this whole book, it doesn't just run on the iPad.
وهذا الكتاب بالكامل، لا يشتغل فقط على الأيباد.
It also runs on the iPhone.
بل يشتغل كذلك على الأيفون.
And so you can start reading on your iPad in your living room
وهكذا يمكن أن تبدأ القراءة على الأيباد في غرفة الجلوس
and then pick up where you left off on the iPhone.
ثم الإستمرار حيث وقفت على الأيفون.
And it works the exact same way.
ويشتغل بنفس الطريقة تماما.
You can pinch into any page.
يمكن أن تقرص أي صفحة.
Open it up.
تفتحها.
So that's Push Pop Press' first title,
إذن هذا أول عنوان لـ Push Pop Press،
Al Gore's "Our Choice."
كتاب آل غور "خيارنا."
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Chris Anderson: That's spectacular.
كريس اندرسون: هذا أمر مذهل.
Do you want to be a publisher,
هل تريد أن تكون ناشرا،
a technology licenser?
مرخص تكنولوجيا؟
What is the business here?
ما هي الرؤية الإقتصادية هنا؟
Is this something that other people can do?
هل هذا أمر يمكن للناس الآخرين القيام به؟
MM: Yeah, we're building a tool
مايك ماتاس: نعم، نحن نبني أداة
that makes it really easy for publishers right now to build this content.
تجعل من السهل جدا على الناشرين الآن إنشاء هذا المحتوى.
So Melcher Media's team, who's on the East coast --
وهكذا فريق ميلتشر الإعلامي، الموجود على الساحل الشرقي --
and we're on the West coast, building the software --
ونحن في الساحل الغربي، نطور البرنامج --
takes our tool
يأخذون أداتنا
and, every day, drags in images and text.
و، كل يوم، يضعون فيها صورا ونصوصا.
CA: So you want to license this software to publishers
كريس أندرسون: إذن تريد ترخيص هذا البرنامج للناشرين
to make books as beautiful as that? (MM: Yes.)
لإنتاج كتب بهذا الجمال؟ (مايك ماتاس: نعم.)
All right. Mike, thanks so much.
حسنا إذن. شكرا جزيلا مايك.
MM: Thank you. (CA: Good luck.)
مايك ماتاس: شكرا لك. (كريس أندرسون: حظا سعيدا.)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)